摩根
Morgan?
为什么
Wh… why?
下次你就有选择了
It'll give you some choices next time.
我都没发现
Didn't even notice.
你拿回了摩托
Got your bike back.
是啊
Yeah.
你还有烟吗
You got another one of those?
谢谢
Thanks.
你在烧毁的森林里
Those people you met,
遇到的那些人抢走了你的摩托
the ones in the burnt forest, they took it from you?
是的
Yeah.
你救了他们 对吧
You saved them, right?
抱歉
Sorry.
你就是这种人
It's who you are.
我们依然受制于此
We're still stuck with that.
我们没有
No, we ain't.
我该杀了他们的
I should've killed them.
带走你和玛姬的那伙人
The ones that took you and Maggie…
他们对你们做了什么
what'd they do to you?
对我们吗
To us?
他们什么也没做
They didn't do anything.
《行尸走肉》
所以如果你还没有计划
So, if you didn't already have plans,
我打算在牛肉干里加酸奶和蘑菇
I was thinking of making my beef jerky stroganoff.
挺好的 谢谢
I'm good, thanks.
虽然不是上等牛排
It's not exactly a nice porterhouse,
但我保证比听起来好吃
but I promise it's better than it sounds.
肯定是
I'm sure it is.
怎么了
What?
我们算什么
What are we doing?
告诉我吧 哪样我都接受
Just tell me. It's good either way.
真的
It really is.
好吧
Okay.
- 我们算「好吧」 - 我们一起吃晚餐
- Okay is what we're doing? - We'll do dinner.
好吗
Okay?
好
All right.
回头见
See you then.
好
Okay.
我没听见你们说话
I didn't hear you guys.
很好
Good.
今天的课在死巷里上
Today's lesson will be in the Cul-de-sac.
实际上 我们能做点别的事吗
Actually, can we do something else?
我离开特区后 就一直开车
After I got out of DC, I just drove.
我记得在我意识到
I remember seeing it right.
自己不知道该去哪时看到过它
when I realized I had no idea where I was going.
爱迪生药品和精品店
Edison's Apothecary and Boutique.
那是沿公路商业区的一家小礼品店
It's just this little gift shop in a strip mall,
但如果那真是药店
but if it's really an apothecary,
那就有药
they had drugs.
你怎么知道药还在那里
How do you know they still got 'em?
那里不算远 我只是想去看看
It isn't that far. I just wanna check.
你和罗西塔没有外出搜索补给或者轮班
And you and Rosita aren't out scavenging or pulling shifts.
我们会去
We'll go.
我想去看看
I wanted to check.
我只是想帮忙
I just wanted to help.
你在外面待过多长时间
How much time you spend out there?
- 没待过 - 想都别想
- None. - Forget it.
我能辨别药物 如今我也会用砍刀了
I can ID the meds. I know how to use a machete now.
我近距离遭遇过行尸
I've seen roamers up close.
我准备好了
I'm ready.
- 你同意吗 - 不
- You good with this? - No.
我会独自去的 假如有必要的话
I'll go alone, if I have to.
你会独自死在外面的
You'll die alone.
我就是在请求你确保我不会死
I'm asking you to make sure I don't.
我才不要一个人照顾她呢
I'm not babysitting her by myself.
这个…
It… the…
什么
What?
没事
Forget it.
到底怎么了
No, what?
我觉得你也许离合松得太快了
I think maybe you're disengaging it too soon.
我15岁就开始开手动挡了
I've been driving stick since I was 15,
经常开像这样的破卡车
usually beat-up trucks like this.
就是在之前…我离开家之前
I mean, before… you know, before I left home.
我兄弟教我的 所以我知道
My brother taught me, so I just know.
达里尔
Daryl.
看到了
Yep.
待在这里
Stay here.
我来
I got it.
是突然倒下的
This happened fast.
树腐烂了 不是人为的
Tree rotted out. It wasn't people.
来吧 安全了
Come on, it's clear.
你找到什么了
What'd you find?
几瓶酒 有人要喝吗
Bottles of booze. Any takers?
不了 谢谢
No, thanks.
那等下喝
For later.
我才不会把它们上交食品室呢
I'm not bringing these to the pantry.
我不喝了
I'm good.
我父母嗜酒
They were kind of my parents' thing.
所以我不喜欢喝
Which is why they aren't mine.
车子没办法从这树上开过去
That truck ain't gonna make it past this tree.
- 走吧 我们步行 - 等等
- Come on, let's walk. - Hold up.
沿着铁路走不用绕弯路
Looks like a straight shot if we follow the tracks.
不行
No.
不走铁路 我们走公路
No tracks. We'll take the road.
那边远了两倍
That's twice as far.
你想走哪边走哪边
Go whichever way you like.
反正我是不会走铁路的
I ain't taking no tracks.
我们应该统一行动
We should stick together.
我看你把你那披肩长发绑起来了
I see you've tied back your Tennessee waterfall there.
我不会撒谎否认我喜欢它
I won't lie. I liked it.
我也许会很想念它的
I may very well miss it.
那种微风吹过 长发飘飘的感觉
The feeling of the billowy curtain catching the breeze.
在某些时候可是极乐享受
some days was straight-up bliss.
但事实是 发型不能让男人成为男人
But brass tacks… the hair doesn't make the man,
硬汉才能让男人成为男人
the man makes the man.
放哨 武器训练 改变发型
Guard duty, weapons training, changing up the hairstyle,
对着女士们显摆 自信吹牛皮
swigging some swagger with the ladies, spitting game…
如果连自信都没有 你就是个弱菜
If you don't spit game, you are game.
你似乎有所改变啊
Man seems to be changing.
至少是在很努力地改变自己
At least trying like hell to.
让我很好奇这是为了什么
Makes me curious what that's about.
很简单 真的
It's simple, really.
在任何角色扮演游戏中
As with any RPG,
无论是桌游 电游 还是其他
tabletop, electronic, or otherwise,
生存的关键就是
the key to survival is allowing oneself.
让自己适应相应的环境
to be shaped by the assigned environment.
这样就会获得很多能力
In doing so, a broad range of capabilities are acquired,
让玩家可以扭转局势并且使用所谓的能力
allowing one to flip the script and use said capabilities.
反过来去塑造环境以维持最长久的生存
to shape said environment for maximum longevity.
我是说我已经处在第二阶段了
I'm saying I'm in the process of said stage two.
我变了 适应了 我是一个生存者
I've changed, adapted. I'm a survivor.
继续骗自己吧
Keep telling yourself that.
我变了 适应了 我是一个生存者
I've changed, adapted. I've become a survivor.
总算到了
About time.
我不是故意选他而不选你的
I didn't mean to pick him over you back there.
只是…
It's just…
你握法不对 要这样
You're holding it wrong. Like this.
谢了
Thanks.
谁教你的
Who taught you?
谁教你战斗的
You know, how to fight?
抱歉 我不是有意提起…
Sorry, I didn't mean to bring up…
很多人教了我很多事
A lot of people taught me a lot of things.
从今往后 他只是长名单中的一个而已
Years from now, he'll just be a name in a long list of names.
（爱迪生药品和精品店）
好了 我和她进去
All right, me and her are gonna do this.
你留在后面 知道吗
You're gonna stay back, got it?
标准弹子锁
Standard pin and tumbler.
滴答几下 容易得很
Tick-tick-click, easy peasy.
这就是那地方
This the place?
没错
It is indeed.
好的
Okay.
你差不多该揭晓答案了
You about ready to spill the pintos.
我们到底来这干嘛
on what the hell it is we're doing here?
尤金
Eugene.
我们要在这生产子弹
We're gonna manufacture bullets here.
我考虑这个问题好几天了
I've been chewing the cud on this for a few days now.
山顶寨没有弹药 我们的物资有限
The Hilltop's dry, our supply's finite.
所以子弹不仅是防卫关键
So not only are bullets vital for defense,
同样也适用于供求法则
but per the law of supply and demand,
一盒子弹现在就是流通货币
a full cartridge is now the coin of the land.
从零开始造子弹
Making bullets from scratch.
利用用过的弹壳 我们在里面装东西
Spent casings, but the innards are all us.
我说的我们 其实就是我
And by us, I mean me.
你认为你能做到吗
And you think you can do that…
就在这吗
here?
就用这个
With just this?
这地方是要彻底清理一遍
Well, the digs will require a thorough scrubbing.
我们得找非常多的铅 但没错
We'll have to scare up a hella ton of lead, but, yes.
我确定一定以及肯定我能做到
I most definitely almost certainly think I can do that here.
我的朋友 那真是个
That, my friend, is some damn fine.
超棒的开创性主意
genuine outside-the-box thinking.
从哪开始
Where do we start?
我们应该通知瑞克 和奥利维亚谈谈
Well, we should inform Rick, talk with Olivia,
看看哪种弹药最值得生产
see what types of ammo would be most valuable to produce.
暂停一下 好让我解决你身后的东西
I'm gonna hit pause so I can kill that thing behind you.
你别动 红毛
Pump your brakes, Red.
这个正式归我了
I'm formally calling dibs on this one.
我的就是我的
Dibs is dibs.
好啊 随便你
Well, be my guest.
干掉它
Get some.
一振
Strike one.
二振
Strike two.
你为什么…
Why did you…?
我说了这个归我
I called dibs.
你没有权利这么做
You had zero authority to…
做什么
To what?
救你一命吗
Stop you from dying?
我刚自己能应付得了
I had full control of the situation.
你连坨屎都应付不了
You had better luck picking up a turd by its clean end.
你要为刚说的话道歉
I'm gonna allow you to apologize for saying that.
现在就给我道歉
So how about you do so right now?
这家伙差点把你的脸啃掉 蠢蛋
Timmy down there almost ate your face, dumbass.
恕我直言 去你的
All due respect, screw you.
你再说一遍
Beg your pardon?
处理行尸在我的能力范围之内
Dispatching walkers is well within my skill set,
所以你要是不同意 就去你的吧
so screw you for suggesting otherwise.
让我先把话说清楚 好吧
Let me get something straight, all right?
动动脑子 自制弹药这类事
Using your cabeza, this whole DIY ammo thing,
那才在你的能力范围之内
that is your damn skill set,
就像对付敌人
just like ghosting hostiles,
包括行尸和活人 那是我的能力之内的事
both of the undead and the living variety, is mine.
你要真想在这个世界活得长久
Now, you truly want to survive this world long-term,
我建议你立马认清这点
I suggest you learn that posthaste.
好的
Okay.
谢谢你保护我
Thank you for your protection.
从休斯顿到这一路上我都需要你的保护
I most certainly needed it between here and Houston.
但我不再需要你的保护了
But your services are no longer required.
这是实话 大实话
The truth, plain and honest.
你对我已经没有用了
You've outlived your usefulness to me.
是吗
Is that so?
大实话
Plain and honest.
- 你要去哪 - 回家
- Where are you going? - Home.
反正你都不需要我的保护了
My services are no longer required.
你自己想办法回去吧
Find your own way back.
混蛋
Asshole.
你这是要把早餐吐出来吗
We gonna find out what you had for breakfast?
燕麦
Oatmeal.
先告诉你一声
Just so you know.
（药品）
要让我帮你拿包吗
You want me to hold your bags, or…?
把药放在柜台上 我告诉你需要哪些
If you set 'em on the counter, I can tell you which.
不 全都带走
No, we're gonna take it all.
你确定吗 因为
Are you sure? Because…
不 没事
No, it's fine.
只有一只而已
It's just one.
听起来像是被困住了
It sounds like it's stuck.
（安静 安静 安静）
你在搞什么鬼
What the hell are you doing?
没什么
Nothing.
（丹尼斯）
你能找到这个地方是好样的
You did good finding this place.
我之前就试图告诉你 你还没准备好
Tried to tell you you weren't ready.
我们都试过
We both did.
我知道
I know.
他比你年纪大还是小
So was he older or younger?
比我大
Older.
大我六分钟
By six minutes.
丹尼斯和迪尼斯这名字是我爸妈
My parents came up with the Dennis/Denise thing.
喝醉了的时候想出来的
on one of their benders.
很好笑吧
Hilarious, right?
什么都吓不到他
Nothing scared him.
他很勇敢
He was brave.
他的脾气也很暴躁
He was angry, too.
这两者的组合有点危险
It's kind of a dangerous combination.
听起来我们的哥哥差不多
Sounds like we had the same brother.
走这条路更近 对吧
This way's faster, right?
车里有个冰箱
There's a cooler in there!
里面可能有什么有用的东西
Might be something we can use inside.
我们已经拿到想要的东西了
We got what we came for.
别去了 没必要费这个事 走吧
Nah, ain't worth the trouble, come on.
该死
Shit.
不 别过来
No, don't!
天啊
Oh, man.
我都吐在我的眼镜上了
I threw up on my glasses.
太好了
Hot damn.
你刚刚闹的是哪一出
What the hell was that?
你可能会没命的 你知不知道
You could've died right there, you know that?
我知道
Yeah, I do.
- 你听懂了没有 - 谁他妈在乎
- Are you hearing me? - Who gives a shit?
你杀那些救世军时也可能会没命
You could've died killing those Saviors,
你们俩都是 但你们没有死
both of you, but you didn't.
要想活下来 就得冒险
You wanna live, you take chances.
就是这样
That's how it works.
那就是我刚做的事
That's what I did.
就为了几罐破汽水吗
For a couple of damn sodas?
不
Nope.
只为了这一罐
Just this one.
你真的这么蠢吗
Are you seriously that stupid?
你呢
Are you?
我说真的 你呢
I mean it. Are you?
你到底知不知道 刚刚的行为对我的意义
Do you have any clue what that was to me,
这整件事对我意味着什么
what this whole thing is to me?
我受过训练
See, I have training in this shit.
我不是在瞎蒙
I'm not making it up as I go along,
不像缝针和手术那些事…
like with the stitches and the surgery and the…
我要你跟我一起来
I asked you to come with me.
是因为你跟我哥哥一样勇敢
because you're brave like my brother.
有时你让我觉得很安全
and sometimes you actually make me feel safe.
我要你一起来是因为你孤身一人
And I wanted you here because you're alone.
或许这是你这辈子第一次孤身一人
Probably for the first time in your life.
也因为你比你想象中更强
And because you're stronger than you think you are,
那让我觉得 也许我也能像你那样
which gives me hope that maybe I can be, too.
我本来可以跟塔拉一起走
I could've gone with Tara.
我本来能告诉她我爱她
I could've told her I loved her,
但是我没有 因为我害怕
but I didn't because I was afraid.
那才是真的蠢
That's what's stupid.
不敢出来 不敢面对自己的恐惧和懦弱
Not coming out here, not facing my shit.
让我觉得更加难受的是
And it makes me sick.
你们甚至都不需要去尝试
that you guys aren't even trying.
因为你们是那么强 那么聪明
because you're strong and you're smart.
你们都是这么好的人
and you're both really good people,
如果你们不醒…
and if you don't wake…
一醒…
up…
面对你们的…
and face your…
立刻放下枪
You drop 'em now!
见鬼
Well, hell.
你有话要对我说吗
You got something to say to me?
你要消除误会
You gonna clear the air?
继续耀武扬威
Step up on that high horse?
不
No.
你话不多
You don't talk much.
还在学怎么用它
Still getting the hang of her.
冲劲很大 但是…
Kicks like a bitch, but…
- 我应该下手的 - 什么
- I should've done it. - Oh, what's that?
说真的 我没听清
Seriously, I didn't catch what you said.
我当时应该杀死你的
I should've killed you.
是啊 你大概是该这么做
Yeah, you probably should've.
现在我们都在这了
So, here we are.
问题就来了 对吗
Kind of begs the question, right?
这事是谁先挑的头
Who brought this on who?
是啊 我知道
I mean, I get that you'll.
我说什么你都得听 但是…
just have to take my word for this, but…
我瞄准的不是她
she wasn't even the one I was aiming for.
我刚才说了 这玩意冲劲挺大
Like I said, kicks like a bitch.
并不是针对谁
It's nothing personal.
我们并不想这样谈新生意
Look, this isn't how we like to start new business arrangements,
但是你们这群混球先定了基调 不是吗
but, well, you pricks kind of set the tone, didn't you?
你想要什么
What do you want?
抱歉亲爱的 我还不知道你叫什么
I'm sorry, darlin', I didn't catch your name.
我叫D 或者德怀特
I'm D, or Dwight.
两种称呼都可以
You can call me either.
然后呢
So?
你叫什么
What's your name?
罗西塔 你想要什么
Rosita. What do you want?
是这样 罗西塔
Well, Rosita…
问题不是我想要什么
it's not what I want.
而是你和达里尔要做什么
It's what you and Daryl are going to do.
你们得带我们进你们的小社区
You're going to let us into your little complex.
里面看起来真的很美
It looks like it's just beautiful in there.
然后你们会让我们带走想要的任何东西
And then you're going to let us take whatever.
和任何人
and whoever we want…
不然我们就爆了尤金的头
or we blow Eugene's brains out.
然后是你
And then yours.
然后是他
And then his.
我真的不希望走到那一步
I hope it doesn't come to that, really.
其他人都不需要死
Nobody else has to die.
我们只想杀一个开开场
We just try and start with one.
你知道的
You know…
保证产生最大的威慑力
maximum impact to get our point across.
怎么办呢 你告诉我
So what's it gonna be? You tell me.
你要想杀人 先杀那边油桶后面
You wanna kill someone, you start with our companion.
躲着的我们的人
hiding over there behind the oil barrels.
他是个一等一的混蛋
He's a first-class a-hole.
比我们三个该死多了
and he deserves it so much more than us three.
去检查一下
Go check it out.
后退 撤退
Fall back! Fall back!
达里尔 别追了
Daryl, stop!
瑞克过来了
Rick's coming.
他怎么样
How is he?
子弹只是擦伤了他
Bullet just grazed him,
还好我们把他及时救了回来
but it's a good thing we got him back when we did.
我们拿到的抗生素可以防止他感染
Antibiotics we picked up could save him from an infection.
可以救他的命
Could save his life.
这是丹妮斯的功劳
That's what Denise did.
你醒了吗
You here?
醒了
Present.
很好
Good.
我不是想杀你
I was not trying to kill you.
我在寻找时机
I was looking for a moment.
你找到了
You found it.
你要为质疑我的能力道歉吗
Do you apologize for questioning my skills?
我为质疑你的能力道歉
I apologize for questioning your skills.
你咬鸡鸡的本事真强 尤金
You know how to bite a dick, Eugene.
我是满怀敬意说出这话的
I mean that with the utmost of respect.
欢迎来到第二阶段
Welcome to stage two.
不用欢迎我
Don't need to welcome me.
我来到第二阶段有阵子了
I've been here a while.
我刚听说了
I just heard.
你还好吗
You okay?
你说过我有选择
You said I had choices.
你也有选择
You have them, too.
我们也许会在这里过三十年
Could be 30 years for us here.
但那还是不够
That's still too short.
进来吧
Come inside.
你说的对
You were right.
你说的时候我就知道了
I knew it when you said it.
我希望这一切不必结束
I wish it didn't have to end,
至少不是以这种方式
not this way.
我从来不想伤害你
It was never my intention to hurt you,
但是必须这样
but it's how it has to be.
我们在这里拥有很多
We have so much here…
人 食物 药品 围墙
people, food, medicine, walls,
一切生存必需品
everything we need to live.
但是我们有的东西 其他人也想要
But what we have other people want, too,
这一点永远不会改变
and that will never change.
即便我们撑过了这次威胁 还是没有结束
If we survive this threat and it's not over,
其他人会回来 取代之前的人
another one will be back to take its place,
试图夺走我们的东西
to take what we have.
我爱你们所有人
I love you all here.
真的
I do.
我必须为你们杀人
And I'd have to kill for you.
而我做不到
And I can't.
我不会做
I won't.
瑞克曾驱逐我 我本来永远不会回来
Rick sent me away and I wasn't ever gonna come back,
但是发生了很多事 我最后留了下来
but everything happened and I wound up staying.
但我不能再留下去了
But I can't anymore.
我不能再爱任何人 因为我不能再为任何人杀人
I can't love anyone because I can't kill for anyone.
所以我走了 我早该这样做了
So I'm going, like I always should have.
请别来找我
Don't come after me, please.